A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Latino Liaison Records, 2004-2009
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Latino Liaison Records 2004-2009
The Library of Virginia
44808
3.38 cu. ft. (10 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219, accession 44808 transferred on 14 January 2010.
Historical Information
The Latino Liaison position was created by Governor Mark Warner in November 2002. The Latino Liaison works with the Governor's Office, various governmental agencies both state and local, community organizations, the private sector, and Latino leaders to better serve this growing community. The Latino Liaison also represents the governor on the Virginia Latino Advisory Board, created in 2003. On 19 January 2006 Governor Tim Kaine named Sindy Benavides as Deputy Director of Constituent Services and Latino Liaison. As the Liaison, she provided outreach to Latinos statewide and educated them on available state services. Benavides later served as Director of Appointments for the Secretary of the Commonwealth. In 2009, Benavides joined the Democratic National Committee as the Director of the Community Outreach and Voting Department. On 13 April 2009 Governor Kaine appointed Luisa Soaterna as Latino Liaison. Soaterna served in the office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth since November 2006 where she dealt with constituent services focusing on Spanish speaking clientele.
Scope and Content
The Latino Liaison Records of Governor Timothy M. Kaine are housed in ten boxes. The collection is arranged by subject/topic. These records include agenda's correspondence, memorandums, minutes, notes, reports, presentations, plans, DVDs and project files. These records document the Kaine administration's (2006-2010) outreach to Virginia's Latino community.
Related Material
Office of the Governor-Tim Kaine
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration Electronic Files, Email, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009). Series IV. Secretary of the Commonwealth, Subseries M. Sindy Benavides contains 1055 emails. Sindy M. Benavides served as Deputy Director of Constituent Services (January 2006-September 2006), Director of Gubernatorial Appointments (September 2006-April 2009), and Latino Liaison (January 2006-April 2009). Benavides left the administration in April 2009 to work at the Democratic National Committee as Director of Community Outreach. Series XIX. Constitutent Services, Subseries M. Luisa Soaterna contains 62 emails. Luisa Soaterna served as Special Assistant for Constituent Services and Latino Liaison from 2009 to 2010. Soaterna previously worked in the Authentications Department of the Secretary of the Commonwealth.The Library of Virginia Email Project - Governor Tim Kaine Portal provides access to the Kaine email collection and includes guides to other Kaine administration records.
The Governor Tim Kaine Administration Web Archive Collection, 2006-2010 contains archived versions of websites for the Governor's Office, his initiative sites, and the sites of his cabinet secretaries. Also included are the related sites for the First Lady (Anne Holton), as well as the Lt. Governor (Bill Bolling), and Attorney General (Bob McDonnell and William C. Mims), two statewide officials elected in the same cycle as Governor Kaine.
Contents List
- Virginia Latino Advisory Board (VLAB), 2004-2009.
  The Virginia Latino Advisory Board (VLAB) records are housed in two (2) archival boxes. Records include Background Briefing Binder, 2004-2006; meeting information (including some minutes), 2006-2009; and reports, 2006-2008
  - Background Briefing Binder, 2004-2006 (part one) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Background Briefing Binder, 2004-2006 (part two) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - VLAB and VAAB (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Website (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Meetings, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meetings, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Meetings, 2008 (part one) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Meetings, 2008 (part two) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 2008 Governor's Latino Summit (part one) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 2008 Governor's Latino Summit (part two) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meetings, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report, 2006 (Drafts and Edits) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report, October 2006 (Final) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report, October 2006 (Spanish) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Annual Report, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Subject Files, 2006-2009.
  The Subject Files are housed in six (6) archival boxes. Original order maintained whenever possible. Subjects include: Virginia State Crime Commission, Illegal Immigration Task Force; Inter-Agency Language Services Office; Governor Tim Kaine's 6 February 2008 meeting with El Salvador President Elias Antonio Saca; New American Initiative; planning for 1st Hispanic You Symposium (HYS), 16-19 July 2008; and Spanish Language Initiative. Also included are reference materials (reports, books, directories, etc.).
  - Virginia State Crime Commission, Illegal Immigration Task Force, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Inter-Agency Language Services Office, State Agency Survey, 2007 (part one) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Inter-Agency Language Services Office, State Agency Survey, 2007 (part two) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Inter-Agency Language Services Office, State Agency Survey, 2007 (part three) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Inter-Agency Language Services Office, State Agency Survey, 2007 (part four) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Governor Tim Kaine Meeting with Elias Antonio Saca, President of the Republic of El Salvador, 6 February 2008 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Parent Education Advocacy Training Center, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - New American Initiative, 2007-2009 (part one) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - New American Initiative, 2007-2009 (part two) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Hispanic Chamber of Commerce Gala, 15 April 2008 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Memorandums, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Constituent Correspondence Report, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Schedule for interfaith prayer service for victims of Virginia Tech shooting, 20 April 2007 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Governor Kaine press clippings from Latino media outlets, 2006-2009 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hispanic Outreach at the Virginia Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Housing Development Authority, Advisory Committee, 11 December 2008 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - State Genetics Education Plan Working Group, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Telamon-Virginia, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Governor Tim Kaine's Inaugural Address (Spanish), 16 January 2006 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - American Red Cross, 2007-2009 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Federation for American Immigration Reform (FAIR), 2009 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - New American Initiative, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Legal Resources, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Dept. of Labor publications, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Volunteer Corps, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Council of Churches, 65th Annual Meeting, Church Growth in the Commonwealth, 4-5 November 2009 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Latino - Economy Central Virginia, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Latino Advisory Board, 2006, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Governor's Outreach Commission, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Hispanic Youth Symposium, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Spanish Language Initiative, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Spanish Language Initiative, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Spanish Language Initiative, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Immigration Legislation, 2008 General Assembly (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Vital Records, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Hispanic Health Conference, Program Committee, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Latino Heritage Month, List, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Creciendo Juntos, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Dept. of Emergency Management, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Outreach, 2006-2009 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Outreach, 2006-2009 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Declined Invitations, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Reference Material (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Reference Material (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Reference Material (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Reference Material (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Reference Material (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Pandemic Flu: A Video Guide to Pandemic Preparedness and Response in Virginia, created by the Virginia Department of Health (DVD) (Box 8)
  - Success in the US: Health Care, created by Experience Healthcare (DVD) (Box 8)
  - Virginia State Police Anti-Gang PSA, 2 June 2006 (BETA) (Box 8)
  - Certificate of Recognition, Latino/Hispanic Heritage Month, 15 September-15 October 2008 (3 copies) (Box 8)
- Constituent Correspondence, 2006-2009.
  The Constituent Correspondence are housed in two (2) archival boxes. They contain correspondence and supporting documentation regarding legal, criminal and immigration issues sent to the Office of the Governor and/or Latino Liaison. Confidential, privacy-protected and attorney-client privileged records are closed for 75 years per Code of Virginia, 2.2-2705.1, 2.2-3800 and 42.1-78.
  - 2006 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 2007 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 2008-2009 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Lillian Fuentes, 2007 (part one) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Lillian Fuentes, 2007 (part two) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Lillian Fuentes, 2007 (part three) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lillian Fuentes, 2007 (part four) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Lillian Fuentes, 2007 (part five) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Lillian Fuentes, 2007 (part six) (Box 10, Folder 2)